Miscellaneous Organizations Collection, circa 1824-2011 (ongoing)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES I. NATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS
  - United States (Box 8)
    - West Virginia Garden Club, Inc.: pamphlet, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Woman's Association of Commerce: postcards and bulletin, 1915-17 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Woman's Foundation: reports, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Woman's Municipal League of the City of New York: quarterly, 1912-20 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Woman's National Liberal Union: report, 1890 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Woman's National Wilson and Marshall Organization: correspondence, 1912 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Woman's Relief Corps (Box 18)
      - General, 1916-24, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Order Book, 1884-94 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Woman's Republican Association: pamphlet, 1892 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Women for Racial and Economic Equality (WREE), undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Women of Color Community Task Force, 2011 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Women of Goodwill (WOGS): pamphlet, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Women of the Ku Klux Klan: pamphlet, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Women USA: pamphlets and mailings, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Women's Educational and Industrial Union, Boston: pamphlets, books, clippings, and correspondence, 1877-1976 (Box 18, Folder 16-18)
    - Women's Information Services Network: correspondence, memos, and minutes, 1975-78 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Women's Joint Congressional Committee: pamphlet, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Women's League of Brooklyn: correspondence, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Women's League for Conservative Judaism: book and packet, 1968-76 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Women's Legal Defense Fund: pamphlet, articles, and press releases, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Women's Municipal League of Boston: pamphlet, 1926 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Women's National Committee for Law Enforcement: pamphlets, and newsletter, 1926-27 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Women's National Indian Association: pamphlets, 1891-99 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Women's National Radio Committee: newsletter, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Women's Overseas Service League: Lest We Forget…A History of the Women's Overseas Service League by Helene M. Sillia, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Women's Patriotic Association for Diminishing the Use of Imported Luxuries, NY: pamphlets, 1864 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Women's Rest Tour Association, Boston: historical pamphlet by Helen Rich Norton, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Women's Social, Industrial Association, New Orleans: constitution, 1881 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Women's Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Association, NYC: newsletters and pamphlets, 1941-51 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- SERIES II. INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS
  - "Internationale Frauenorganisationen": manuscript by Dr. Dorothee von Velsen, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - La Abogada Internacional (The International Woman Lawyer): newsletters, 1958-67 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Associated Countrywomen of the World (ACWW) (Box 20)
    - General, 1941-61, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Conference, 1936-62 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
    - History of the Associated Countrywomen of the World by Neve Scarborough, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Association for Women in Development (AWID): mailing, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Central and East European Women's Federation in Exile, London: correspondence, 1955-56 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Committee for Asian Women (CAW), 2002 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - GEDOK: Union of Women Artists' and Art Lovers' Associations: pamphlets, 1950-61 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - International Archive for the Women's Movement, Amsterdam (Box 21)
    - Pamphlets, bibliography, correspondence, and newsletters, 1937-80, undated (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Yearbook, 1937-38 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - International Assembly of Women: clippings, book, and article, 1946-60 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
  - International Congress of Women, The Hague: press release, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - International Convention of Women: photograph, 1938, [see Oversize Materials] (Box 21)
  - International Cooperative Women's Guild: clippings and correspondence, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - International Council of Social Democratic Women: bulletins, 1959-74 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - International Federation of Business and Professional Women: proceedings, reports, clippings, and correspondence, 1930-50 (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
  - International Federation of University Women (Box 21)
    - General, 1922-68, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Conferences (Box 21)
      - 1924, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - 1929-39 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Council meetings, 1925-37 (Box 22, Folder 2-4)
  - International Federation of Women in Legal Careers, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - International Planned Parenthood Federation, [see separate boxes] (Box 22)
  - ISIS Women's International Information and Communication Service: correspondence, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - League of Nations: reports and pamphlets, 1923-48 [see also UN] (Box 22)
    - Status of women, 1923-37 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Committee for the Study of the Legal Status of Women, 1938-48, undated (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
  - Liaison Committee of Women's International Organizations: pamphlets, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - MADRE, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Pan-American League: pamphlet, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Pan-American Women's Association, 1961-66 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Peace Corps: clippings, pamphlets, study guides, minutes, and correspondence, 1938-65 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Soroptimist: pamphlets, correspondence, and book, 1948-71 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - United Nations organizations, [see separate boxes] (Box 22)
  - Women's World Fellowship, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - World Center for Women's Archives: clippings and pamphlets, 1935-67 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - World Organization of Mothers of all Nations: correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - World Woman's Party: certificate, pamphlets, bulletin, article, and correspondence, 1938-46 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - World's YWCA, [see also YWCA Records in the Sophia Smith Collection] (Box 22)
    - General: pamphlets, annual reports, and clippings, 1902-51 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Study on the Place and Contribution of Women, 1936-38 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Zonta: clippings and magazine, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - International Planned Parenthood Federation (Box 22)
    - Books (Box 22a)
      - Teenage Pregnancy in the Caribbean by Tirbani P. Jagdeo, 1984 (Box 22a)
      - Planejamento Familiar: Aspectos Sociais e Politicos by Walter Rodrigues, 1980 (Box 22a)
    - Pamphlets (Box 22a)
      - English, 1962-84, undated (Box 22a, Folder 1)
      - Portuguese, 1965-81, undated (Box 22a, Folder 2-3)
      - Spanish, 1976-84 (Box 22a, Folder 4)
      - By Walter Rodrigues, 1978-81, undated (Box 22a, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous 1975-1985, undated (Box 22a, Folder 6)
    - "Open File", 1980-81 (Box 22a, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (Box 22a)
      - United Nations 1961-1975, undated (Box 22b, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous 1976, undated (Box 22b, Folder 2)
    - Posters, 1983, undated (Box 22b, Folder 3)
  - United Nations organizations [unprocessed] (Box 22b)
    - General and miscellaneous (Box 22b)
      - Clippings, 1945-77 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Department of Economic and Social Affairs: reports, 1972-75 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Economic and Social Council, Commission on Human Rights, UNICEF: news, 1951-54 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Exchange Report, [see Oversize Materials] (Box 23)
      - International Women's Tribune Centre: pamphlets and flyers, 1977, [see also IWTC Records in Sophia Smith Collection] (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Participation of Women in Public Life Countries: seminar reports, 1957-71 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Rights of Women: press releases, pamphlets, and reports, 1947-73 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Status of Women: A Select Bibliography (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Women in the United Nations: Business and Professional Women's Foundation: press release and publications, 1953-73 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Conventions affecting women, Digest of the position of the UN: pamphlets, 1958-83 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Dumbarton Oaks Plan: pamphlets, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Population Crisis Report, What the United Nations is Doing for the Status of Women, United Nations 15, 1971-72 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - The Situation of Women in the United Nations, UNITAR: clippings and pamphlets, 1972-75 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Women in the United Nations, by Frances W. Kerr, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Women United for the United Nations: clippings and information, 1953-74 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Commission on the Status of Women (Box 24)
      - General: reports, pamphlets, press release, and correspondence, 1945-73 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Declaration of Human Rights: articles, newspaper, pamphlets, reports, and press releases, 1947-63 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Reports, 1982-84 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Resolutions, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Reports, 1946-59 (Box 25, Folder 1-12)
      - Photographs of members, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - By-laws, correspondence, reports, and clippings, 1933-67 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Federation Highlights (newsletter), 1949-51 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Handbook, pamphlets, books, and packet, 1935-72 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - International Women's Year (Box 26)
      - General (Box 26)
        - Bulletins, 1974-76 (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Business and Professional Women's Foundation: Info Digest, circa 1974 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - International Women's Year Stamp: envelope and press release, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Reprints, articles, pamphlets and bulletins, 1974-78 (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Reston Test Survey: survey and correspondence, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - UNICEF and UNESCO: pamphlets, facts, reports, and poster, 1972-75 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - UN Newsletter on the Status of Women, 1964-74 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - UN publications: pamphlets, facts, magazine, press release, and poster, 1974-76 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - World Congress for International Women's Year, Berlin, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Mexico (Box 27)
        - Report, 1975 (Box 27)
        - Conference Agenda: pamphlets and bulletins, 1968-75 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - General: articles, pamphlets, and reports, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Slide and tape show: cassette tape, newsletters, and slides, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - United States Center for International Women's Year (Box 28)
        - General: sticker and clippings, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Newsletter, 1974-77 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - United States Center for International Women's Year, Washington, DC: information, needlepoint pattern, and pamphlets, 1974-75 (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - The Year Became a Decade, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Posters, [see Oversize Materials] (Box 29)
    - Decade for Women, [see Oversize Materials] (Box 29)
      - General, 1976-85 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Bulletins 1978-85 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Mid-Decade World Conference of the United Nations Decade for Women, Copenhagen, Denmark (Box 30)
        - General (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - Report, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, China, Non-Governmental Organizations (NGO) Forum Amendments to e/CN.6/1995/2, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Women and Memory Forum (Egypt), 2010-2014, undated (Box 30a)
  - Guide to Women's Organizations by Ellen Anderson, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - International Directory of Women's Development Organizations, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - International Directory of Women's Organizations, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 3)
- SERIES OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - National Council of Women of the U.S.: audiotapes reel-to-reel (Box 31)
    - "Madame Pandit (Waldorf)": Vijaya Lakshmi Pandit speech to the National Council of Women, 22 Jan 1957 [1 reel] (Box 32)
    - "Women's Role in Crime Control": 39th Biennial Meeting of the National Council of Women, 11 Oct 1966 [6 reels] (Box 32-33)
  - International Planned Parenthood Federation: posters, memorabilia, and birth control advertising memo, 1975-82, undated (Box 34)
  - Flat File Miscellaneous items from NATIONAL ORGS: Canada, Match International Center; Pakistan, All-Pakistan Women's Association; U. S., Ladies' Auxiliary of the Grand Army of the Republic; National Women's Party; INTERNATIONAL ORGS: International Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs; World Women's Party (Box 12)
  - INTERNATIONAL ORGS: United Nations Organizations, UN Decade for Women: The Exchange Report (Women in the Third World), circa 1980; International Women's Year: Posters; U.N. Decade posters (Box 12)